<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="trajano.AT.sourceforge.DOT.net">Archimedes Trajano</author>

    <title>PicoServlet Introduction</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
<section name="Introduction">
<p>
This provides a set of utility JSPs that can be used in debugging JNDI trees, 
JMS, JDBC, EJBs and web applications. These JSPs are standalone and do 
not require any dependencies aside from being in a J2EE container. 
The JSPs can also be extracted and put into other projects that might 
have resources that are in the java: tree. This project also serves as a 
sample web application that is integration tested with Cactus. 
</p>
<p>
The target audience for this tool is a J2EE application developer with
knowledge on how to deploy applications to the container.  Another
audience would be the testers as this provides direct access to the JMS and
JDBC resources that is available to the application.
</p>
</section>

<section name="Installation">

<p>
There are three distribution packages for this application: a source 
distribution, an EAR distribution and a WAR distribution.
</p>
<p>
The WAR file can be deployed to any standard J2EE or web container.  It
can also be unzipped to get the JSPs which can be copied into an existing
J2EE application.  The JSPs may also be extracted from the source
distribution to be included into an existing application.
</p>
<p>
The EAR file can be deployed to any standard J2EE container.  This
distribution is primarily deployed on servers used by the test team.  The
context root is /util.
</p>
</section>

<section name="The Files">
	<section name="db.jsp">
		This JSP file provides access to JDBC resources that are registered in the 
		default JNDI tree.
	</section>
	<section name="ejb.jsp">
		This JSP file lists all the methods available in an EJB when provided with a
		registered EJB Home in the default JNDI tree.
	</section>
	<section name="env.jsp">
		This JSP file outputs all the system properties, session attributes and 
		cookies.  Normally this would be copied into the application to check what
		values the application sets in the session.
	</section>
	<section name="jms.jsp">
		This JSP file sends a text message to a JMS queue.
	</section>
	<section name="jmsbrowser.jsp">
		This JSP file browses the contents of a JMS queue and provides a way
		of clearing the contents of the queue.
	</section>
	<section name="jndi.jsp">
		This JSP file provides way of browsing JNDI trees.  It can use the default
		or the a user defined JNDI context.
	</section>
	<section name="jndi-web.jsp">
		This JSP file provides way of browsing JNDI trees.  It can use the default
		or the a user defined JNDI context.  This is a modified version that
		would support web only containers.
	</section>
</section>
	</body>
</document>
